# MISHLEY OTIENDE

+254746034370



mishleyotiende@gmail.com



Nairobi, Kenya



# SUMMARY

Seasoned associate with over 4 years experience in an international youth-run NGO (AIESEC) and with 2 years experience in the finance world at EY and the TSA. Managed multiple social impact projects including social impact projects for the United Nations Academic Impact through the Millenium Fellowship. Continuous learner and passionate about youth leadership. Proud graduate of the McKinsey Connected Leaders Academy and the Jim Leech Mastercard Foundation Fellowship. Passionate about data analytics.

## **EDUCATION**

**Audit Associate** 

# McKinsey Product, Engineering and Leadership Academy

April 2023 - July 2024 (11 Months)
Learned some key concepts on Product
Management and how to leverage AI/ML for
efficient work processes. Took a course on self
and team leadership under the Connected
Leaders Academy.

#### Udacity - Access Bank Scholarship

June 2023 - Aug 2023 (3 months) Business Analytics Fundamentals

#### Queen's University

Dec 2022 - March 2023 (4 months)
Part of the Jim Leech Mastercard Foundation
Fellowship under the Dunin-Deshpande Queens
Innovation Center. Pursued a certificate in Design
Thinking, High Performance Teams and
Entrepreneurship.

#### **Moi University**

Aug 2017 - May 2023 (5 years)
Bachelor of Engineering in Electrical and
Telecommunications Engineering. Was part of
AIESEC, Technology Students Association and
the Moi University Peer Council Movement.
Served as Academics Director in the Students'
Council.

Expected Honors: Second Upper with Honors.

#### The Aga Khan High School, Mombasa

2012 - 2016

Kenya Certificate of Secondary Education. Grade: A- (minus) of 78 AGP.

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### **Experienced Associate**

EY | August 2024 - Present

 Taken part in multiple projects in different consumer industries, with an additional understanding in financial and bank institutions.

#### **Associate**

EY | September 2023 - August 2024

- Currently working under the department of Consumer and Industrial Goods. Functioning in a multicultural teams to conduct value-driven audits to different clients.
- Been part of projects in the oil and gas industries; consumer sector; hospitality industry, and electrical and energy providers.
- Volunteered more than 40 hours to sustainability projects under EY Ripples.
- Earned badge for training in Finance, Artificial Intelligence, Oil and Gas and Data and Information Strategy.

#### **Branch Manager**

AIESEC in Kenya | Feb 2023 - Feb 2024

- Pioneered the McKinsey Connected Leaders Academy within the organization which drew participation from over 150 youth members in the different cohorts.
- Led a team of 8 portfolios (departments) that managed 5
  awards. These awards constituted the Overrall Best Entity (out
  of the 10 other entities under AIESEC in Kenya), and 4 portfolio
  awards in the following departments: Finance, Legalities and
  Administration; Business Development; Brand and Customer
  Experience (B2C Category), and the Engagement with AIESEC
  portfolio (equivalent of the Product Management Portfolio).
- Managed to improve brand presence by leading recruitment efforts at 2 other satellite campuses: College of Health Sciences and Annex Campus.

# **CERTIFICATIONS**

- August 2024 | EY Oil and Gas
- July 2024 | EY Artificial Intelligence
- July 2024 | EY Finance
- November 2023 | EY Data and Information Strategy
- September 2023 | Climate Risk An Introduction (NASBA)
- June 2023 | KPMG Virtual Advisory Programme
- June 2023 | Accenture Strategy Consulting Virtual Experience Programme
- May 2023 | McKinsey & Co. Product Academy Foundations
- Mar 2023 | McKinsey & Co. Forward Programme
- Jan 2023 | Introduction to Python, Kaggle
- August 2022 | Networking Fundamentals, LinkedIn

# **AWARDS**

- Sep 2022 | Top 20 Moonshot Borderless Awards.
   Project name: AverTeach. Focus was transitioning LGBTQ refugees into employability and entrepreneurship pipeline.
- Apr 2022 | Technology Students Association Award (Software and Cybersecurity Category, Second Runnerup)
- July 2016 | Honoris Causa, The Aga Khan High School
- April 2013 | Outstanding Delegate Award in International Involvement, United Nations and the Aga Khan Academy

## **FELLOWSHIPS**

- Jim Leech Mastercard Foundation Fellowship
- McKinsey Forward Programme
- Millennium Fellowship, United Nations Academic Impact (UNAI)

As the Member Subcommittee Chair, successfully led 1
membership audit with a team of 3 alongside the National
Director in charge of Organizational Development.

# Vice President (Finance, Legalities and Administration)

AIESEC in Moi University | Feb 2022 - Feb 2023

- Successfully conducted a 2-week Financial Literacy Programme, targeting 69 participants from different campuses within Kenya, and having an attendance of 8 companies including CIC Insurance, Post Bank, Kenya Financial Education Center, among others.
- Bolstering budget implementation by 18% in the first quarter and generating 54% of projected income in first quarter of service.

# Organizing Committee Manager (UjuziHub)

AIESEC in Moi University | April 2022 - September 2022

- Managed to diversify product line by segmenting offerings into different topical series; therefore, leading to an increase of 201% in the revenue streams for the above initiative.
- Recruited and onboarded 6 members into the committee and achieved more than 67% member retention.

#### Sales Representative

AIESEC in the Middle East and Africa | May 2022 - October 2022

The Youth Speak Forum is a global seminar held by AIESEC annually and it aims at bringing youth together to facilitate the solving of the different societal problems through relevant and sustainable development projects. In 2021, the conference took part in Dubai and commanded attendance from not only more than 20 African countries, but also countries in the Middle East. In 2022, I get to be part of the planning and management team for the conference which is to take place in Rwanda.

#### **Duties and Responsibilities**

- Responsible for sales to corporates.
- Coordinates with Regional Managers BD for global and regional contact lists and entity partners
- Communication with externals
- Responsible for conference sales to externals and Alumni
- Responsible for contract signage follow up

#### **Finance Secretary**

Technology Students Association | July 2021 - June 2022

- Managed to introduce the usage of an accounting software (Odoo) with a view to promoting transparency with different stakeholders and the school administration.
- Organized different networking spaces for student engineers, such as the Corporate Dinner, which attained an attendance of 86 students within the Moi University engineering fraternity, and 1 alumnus.
- Managed the organizing of different events including inter alia a corporate dinner and TSA Career Fair.
- Ensured member development through delegation of duties to my members and conducting 1 grant writing seminar.